A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, Office Files of Lisa Mensah FA511
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development, Office Files of Lisa Mensah
1988-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Mensah, Lisa A.
Ford Foundation
FA511
2.62 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Records remain as received.
Biographical / Historical
Lisa Mensah is a foundation executive whose work has focused on economic development and economic security. For more than ten years, Mensah worked at the Ford Foundation. She started as a Program Officer in the Rural Poverty and Resources Program before becoming Deputy Director of the program. Following a reorganization of the Foundation's program structure, she was made Deputy Director of the Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Economic Development unit.
Mensah's post-Ford Foundation positions included her time as Executive Director of the Initiative on Financial Security at the Aspen Institute. She served in the United States Government as Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development during the Obama Administration, and she became President and CEO of the Opportunity Finance Network (OFN) in 2017.
Mensah earned a B.A. from Harvard University and an M.A. from The Johns Hopkins University. Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, she worked in commercial banking at Citibank.
Scope and Contents
Grant Files.
- Grant Files, 1988-1999; I
  - California, University of (Davis) -- RGAs, 1992-1996 (Box 1)
  - California, University of (Davis) -- Proposals, 1995 (Box 1)
  - California, University of (Davis) -- Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 1)
  - Calvert Social Investment Foundation -- Proposals, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Calvert Social Investment Foundation -- RGAs, 1991-1995 (Box 1)
  - Calvert Social Investment Foundation -- Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives -- RGAs, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives -- FY 1996 Proposal, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Center for Policy Alternatives -- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Chicago, University of -- RGAs, 1988-1997 (Box 1)
  - Chicago, University of -- Proposals, 1993-1996 (Box 1)
  - Chicago, University of -- Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 1)
  - Coastal Enterprises -- RGAs, 1990-1997 (Box 1)
  - Coastal Enterprises -- $1 Million Reserve Grant, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Coastal Enterprises -- Proposals, 1993-1998 (Box 1)
  - Coastal Enterprises -- Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - The Development Fund -- RGAs, 1988-1995 (Box 1)
  - The Development Fund -- Proposals, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - The Development Fund -- Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - HandsNet -- CG NET, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - HandsNet -- RGAs, 1987-1994 (Box 1)
  - HandsNet -- Proposals, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
  - HandsNet -- Correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box 1)
  - HandsNet -- Presentation, 1998 October 27 (Box 1)
  - HandsNet -- Rural Telecommunications Initiative Steering Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - HandsNet -- Rural Telecommunications Initiative and the HandsNet Rural Issues Forum, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Liaison Files -- RGAs -- A-C (1/7), 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Liaison Files -- RGAs -- D-F (2/7), 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Liaison Files -- RGAs -- G-J (3/7), 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Liaison Files -- RGAs -- K-M (4/7), 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Liaison Files -- RGAs -- N-O (5/7), 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Liaison Files -- RGAs -- P-S (6/7), 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Liaison Files -- RGAs -- T-Z (7/7), 1991-1998 (Box 2)
  - Media for Development International -- FY 98 Grant, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Media for Development International -- Proposal, 1994 July 25 (Box 2)
  - Media for Development International -- Proposals, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Media for Development International -- Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 2)
  - Media for Development International -- RGAs, 1993-1998 (Box 2)
  - Media for Development International -- Publications, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Society for International Development -- Correspondence, 1993-1999 (Box 2)
  - Society for International Development -- Proposals, 1993-1998 (Box 2)
  - Society for International Development -- Publications, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Taos County Economic Development Corp. -- RGAs, 1988-1996 (Box 2)
  - Taos County Economic Development Corp. -- Proposals, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Taos County Economic Development Corp. -- Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 2)